[
  {
    "question": "What is the usage of the <br> tag?",
    "answer_1": "For makeing the text Bold",
    "answer_2": "For making the text Italic",
    "answer_3": "For inserting a single line break",
    "answer_4": "For making Horizontal rule",
    "right_answer": "For inserting a single line break"
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the <img> tag has href arrtibue?",
    "answer_1": "Yes",
    "answer_2": "No, it's for the Acnhor tag <a></a>",
    "answer_3": "All Element has this Attribute",
    "answer_4": "Answer 1 and 3 are right",
    "right_answer": "No, it's for the Acnhor tag <a></a>"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can We make the text bold?",
    "answer_1": "By using the <b> tag",
    "answer_2": "By using the <strong></strong> tag",
    "answer_3": "Customizing it with the font-weight propert in CSS",
    "answer_4": "All answers are right",
    "right_answer": "All answers are right"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Right Hierarchy for creating part of a Page?",
    "answer_1": "<h2> Then <p> Then <h1> Then <p> Then <h3> Then <p> Then <img>",
    "answer_2": "<h1> Then <p> Then <h3> Then <p> Then <h2> Then <p> Then <img>",
    "answer_3": "<h2> Then <p> Then <h3> Then <p> Then <h1> Then <p> Then <img>",
    "answer_4": "All Solutions are Wrong",
    "right_answer": "All Solutions are Wrong"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can We include External Page inside our HTML Page?",
    "answer_1": "By using Include keyword in HTML",
    "answer_2": "By using Load keyword In HTML",
    "answer_3": "By using <iframe></iframe> tag",
    "answer_4": "All Solutions are Wrong",
    "right_answer": "By using <iframe></iframe> tag"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Tag that not exists in HTML5?",
    "answer_1": "<object>",
    "answer_2": "<basefont>",
    "answer_3": "<abbr>",
    "answer_4": "All of the above",
    "right_answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can We specify the Document Type for HTML5 Page?",
    "answer_1": "<DOCTYPE html>",
    "answer_2": "<DOCTYPE html5>",
    "answer_3": "<!DOCTYPE html5>",
    "answer_4": "<!DOCTYPE html>",
    "right_answer": "<!DOCTYPE html>"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the element that's not exists in HTML5 Semantics",
    "answer_1": "<article>",
    "answer_2": "<section>",
    "answer_3": "<blockquote>",
    "answer_4": "<aside>",
    "right_answer": "<blockquote>"
  },
  {
    "question": "In HTML can We use this way to add Attributes?",
    "answer_1": "<div class='class-name'>",
    "answer_2": "<div class=class-name>",
    "answer_3": "<div class=\"class-name\">",
    "answer_4": "All are right",
    "right_answer": "All are right"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who developed Python Programming Language?",
    "answer_1": "Wick van Rossum",
    "answer_2": "Rasmus Lerdorf",
    "answer_3": "Guido van Rossum",
    "answer_4": "Niene Stom",
    "right_answer": "Guido van Rossum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of Programming does Python support?",
    "answer_1": "object-oriented programming",
    "answer_2": "structured programming",
    "answer_3": "functional programming",
    "answer_4": "All of the mentioned",
    "right_answer": "All of the mentioned"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is Python case sensitive when dealing with identifiers?",
    "answer_1": "no",
    "answer_2": "yes",
    "answer_3": "none of the mentioned",
    "answer_4": "machine dependent",
    "right_answer": "yes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the correct extension of the Python file?",
    "answer_1": ".python",
    "answer_2": ".pl",
    "answer_3": ".py",
    "answer_4": ".p",
    "right_answer": ".py"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is Python code compiled or interpreted?",
    "answer_1": "Python code is both compiled and interpreted",
    "answer_2": "Python code is neither compiled nor interpreted",
    "answer_3": "Python code is only compiled",
    "answer_4": "Python code is only interpreted",
    "right_answer": "Python code is both compiled and interpreted"
  },
  {
    "question": "What will be the value of the following Python expression? 4 + 3 % 5",
    "answer_1": "7",
    "answer_2": "2",
    "answer_3": "4",
    "answer_4": "1",
    "right_answer": "7"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is used to define a block of code in Python language?",
    "answer_1": "Indentation",
    "answer_2": "Key",
    "answer_3": "Brackets",
    "answer_4": "All of the mentioned",
    "right_answer": "Indentation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which keyword is used for function in Python language?",
    "answer_1": "Function",
    "answer_2": "def",
    "answer_3": "Fun",
    "answer_4": "Define",
    "right_answer": "def"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following character is used to give single-line comments in Python?",
    "answer_1": "//",
    "answer_2": "#",
    "answer_3": "!",
    "answer_4": "/*",
    "right_answer": "#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Python supports the creation of anonymous functions at runtime, using a construct called _____",
    "answer_1": "pi",
    "answer_2": "anonymous",
    "answer_3": "lambda",
    "answer_4": "none of the mentioned",
    "right_answer": "lambda"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the order of precedence in python?",
    "answer_1": "Exponential, Parentheses, Multiplication, Division, Addition, Subtraction",
    "answer_2": "Exponential, Parentheses, Division, Multiplication, Addition, Subtraction",
    "answer_3": "Parentheses, Exponential, Multiplication, Division, Subtraction, Addition",
    "answer_4": "Parentheses, Exponential, Multiplication, Division, Addition, Subtraction",
    "right_answer": "Parentheses, Exponential, Multiplication, Division, Addition, Subtraction"
  },
  {
    "question": "What will be the output of the following Python code snippet if x=1?  x<<2",
    "answer_1": "4",
    "answer_2": "2",
    "answer_3": "1",
    "answer_4": "8",
    "right_answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does pip stand for python?",
    "answer_1": "Pip Installs Python",
    "answer_2": "Pip Installs Packages",
    "answer_3": "Preferred Installer Program",
    "answer_4": "All of the mentioned",
    "right_answer": "Preferred Installer Program"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true for variable names in Python?",
    "answer_1": "underscore and ampersand are the only two special characters allowed",
    "answer_2": "unlimited length",
    "answer_3": "all private members must have leading and trailing underscores",
    "answer_4": "none of the mentioned",
    "right_answer": "unlimited length"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the truncation division operator in Python?",
    "answer_1": "|",
    "answer_2": "//",
    "answer_3": "/",
    "answer_4": "%",
    "right_answer": "//"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following functions is a built-in function in python?",
    "answer_1": "factorial()",
    "answer_2": "print()",
    "answer_3": "seed()",
    "answer_4": "sqrt()",
    "right_answer": "print()"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the use of id() function in python?",
    "answer_1": "Every object doesn't have a unique id",
    "answer_2": "Id returns the identity of the object",
    "answer_3": "All of the mentioned",
    "answer_4": "sqrt()",
    "right_answer": "Id returns the identity of the object"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a core data type in Python programming?",
    "answer_1": "Tuples",
    "answer_2": "Lists",
    "answer_3": "Class",
    "answer_4": "Dictionary",
    "right_answer": "Class"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is JavaScript?",
    "answer_1": "JavaScript is a scripting language used to make the website interactive",
    "answer_2": "JavaScript is an assembly language used to make the website interactive",
    "answer_3": "JavaScript is a compiled language used to make the website interactive",
    "answer_4": "None of the mentioned",
    "right_answer": "JavaScript is a scripting language used to make the website interactive"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is correct about JavaScript?",
    "answer_1": "JavaScript is an Object-Based language",
    "answer_2": "JavaScript is Assembly-language",
    "answer_3": "JavaScript is an Object-Oriented language",
    "answer_4": "JavaScript is a High-level language",
    "right_answer": "JavaScript is an Object-Based language"
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the given statements, which statement defines closures in JavaScript?",
    "answer_1": "JavaScript is a function that is enclosed with references to its inner function scope",
    "answer_2": "JavaScript is a function that is enclosed with references to its lexical environment",
    "answer_3": "JavaScript is a function that is enclosed with the object to its inner function scope",
    "answer_4": "None of the mentioned",
    "right_answer": "JavaScript is a function that is enclosed with references to its lexical environment"
  },
  {
    "question": "Arrays in JavaScript are defined by which of the following statements?",
    "answer_1": "It is an ordered list of values",
    "answer_2": "It is an ordered list of objects",
    "answer_3": "It is an ordered list of string",
    "answer_4": "None of the mentioned",
    "right_answer": "It is an ordered list of values"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not javascript data types?",
    "answer_1": "Null type",
    "answer_2": "Undefined type",
    "answer_3": "Number type",
    "answer_4": "All of the mentioned",
    "right_answer": "All of the mentioned"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why JavaScript Engine is needed?",
    "answer_1": "Both Compiling & Interpreting the JavaScript",
    "answer_2": "Parsing the javascript",
    "answer_3": "Interpreting the JavaScript",
    "answer_4": "Compiling the JavaScript",
    "right_answer": "Interpreting the JavaScript"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is CSS?",
    "answer_1": "CSS is a style sheet language",
    "answer_2": "CSS is designed to separate the presentation and content, including layout, colors, and fonts",
    "answer_3": "CSS is the language used to style the HTML documents",
    "answer_4": "All of the mentioned",
    "right_answer": "All of the mentioned"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following tag is used to embed css in html page?",
    "answer_1": "<css>",
    "answer_2": "<!DOCTYPE html>",
    "answer_3": "<script>",
    "answer_4": "<style>",
    "right_answer": "<style>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following CSS selectors are used to specify a group of elements?",
    "answer_1": "tag",
    "answer_2": "id",
    "answer_3": "class",
    "answer_4": "both class and tag",
    "right_answer": "class"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following has introduced text, list, box, margin, border, color, and background properties?",
    "answer_1": "HTML",
    "answer_2": "PHP",
    "answer_3": "CSS",
    "answer_4": "Ajax",
    "right_answer": "CSS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following CSS framework is used to create a responsive design?",
    "answer_1": "django",
    "answer_2": "rails",
    "answer_3": "larawell",
    "answer_4": "bootstrap",
    "right_answer": "bootstrap"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following CSS selector is used to specify a rule to bind a particular unique element?",
    "answer_1": "tag",
    "answer_2": "id",
    "answer_3": "class",
    "answer_4": "both class and tag",
    "right_answer": "id"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following type of HTML tag is used to define an internal style sheet?",
    "answer_1": "<script>",
    "answer_2": "<link>",
    "answer_3": "<class>",
    "answer_4": "<style>",
    "right_answer": "<style>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following CSS property is used to make the text bold?",
    "answer_1": "text-decoration: bold",
    "answer_2": "font-weight: bold",
    "answer_3": "font-style: bold",
    "answer_4": "text-align: bold",
    "right_answer": "font-weight: bold"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following CSS style property is used to specify an italic text?",
    "answer_1": "style",
    "answer_2": "font",
    "answer_3": "font-style",
    "answer_4": "@font-face",
    "right_answer": "font-style"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are the CSS Extension Prefixes for Webkit?",
    "answer_1": "-chrome",
    "answer_2": "-web",
    "answer_3": "-o-",
    "answer_4": "-webkit",
    "right_answer": "-webkit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the correct syntax to link an external style sheet in the HTML file?",
    "answer_1": "<link rel=”stylesheet” href=”style.css” />",
    "answer_2": "<link rel=”stylesheet” src=”style.css” />",
    "answer_3": "<style rel=”stylesheet” src=”style.css” />",
    "answer_4": "<style rel=”stylesheet” link=”style.css” />",
    "right_answer": "<link rel=”stylesheet” href=”style.css” />"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the first CSS specification to become an official W3C Recommendation?",
    "answer_1": "CSS level 2",
    "answer_2": "(X)HTML CSS",
    "answer_3": "CSS level 1",
    "answer_4": "CSS level 2.1",
    "right_answer": "CSS level 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following function defines a linear gradient as a CSS image?",
    "answer_1": "gradient()",
    "answer_2": "linear-gradient()",
    "answer_3": "grayscale()",
    "answer_4": "image()",
    "right_answer": "linear-gradient()"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following CSS property can be used to set the image as a border instead of the border style?",
    "answer_1": "background-image-source",
    "answer_2": "background-image",
    "answer_3": "border-image-source",
    "answer_4": "border-image",
    "right_answer": "border-image-source"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following CSS property defines the different properties of all four sides of an element's border in a single declaration?",
    "answer_1": "border-collapse",
    "answer_2": "border-width",
    "answer_3": "padding",
    "answer_4": "border",
    "right_answer": "border-width"
  }
]